Dan Carson

okdan.com | dan@okdan.com | 425-802-2952

Summary

An experienced design leader who sincerely believes design can make a positive difference in people's lives. I am passionate about working with good people to find simple solutions to complex problems.

I am currently the Head of Design and User Experience at Crowdpac, a political data and crowdfunding startup based in San Francisco.

Prior to that I had the experience of a lifetime, as Lead Designer and Transition Design Director for Barack Obama's 2012 re-election campaign.

In between I was a Senior Designer at Modest, a mobile commerce startup acquired by Paypal – and a designer working with great organizations like Open Gov Foundation, Hillary for America, Change.org, Precision Strategies, Northwestern University, Planned Parenthood, and many more.

Experience

Crowdpac

08/2015 - Present

Head of Design and User Experience

Senior member of the product development team where I plan, research, design, build, and test tools that give people around the world a new way to participate in the political process and make an impact.

okdan.com 03/2015 - 8/2015

Design consultant

Innovative, data-driven design that delivers results. Clients include Trunk Club, Change.org, AKPD Media, 270 Strategies, Precision Strategies, Planned Parenthood Action Fund, and the Democratic Party.

Modest, Inc.

02/2014 - 02/2015

Senior Product Designer

Senior Product Designer in charge of UX, interaction design, and user testing. I was responsible for the user experience of our native iOS and Android apps, new retailer onboarding, and store management tools.

Change.org

07/2013 - 11/2013

Product Designer

Focused on the initial public launch of Change.org for Decision Makers - a revolutionary new tool that enables two-way dialog between elected officials and their constituents via the world's most popular online petition platform.

Experience cont'd

Trunk Club Product Designer

02/2013 - 07/2013

Worked on a wide range of products, including optimization of the customer acquisition flow, redesigning the iPhone app, redesigning the public website, and helping implement brand guidelines across multiple platforms.

Obama for America

11/2012 - 02/2013

Design Director

As OFA transitioned from a campaign to a non-profit I managed two other designers, and worked closely with our development and content teams to oversee the delivery of design products supporting the President's agenda.

Obama for America

10/2011 - 11/2012

Lead Interactive Designer

Worked alongside the most talented and passionate group of people I've ever had the pleasure of meeting. I collaborated every day with our field organization, technology, and digital teams to create tools and experiences that engaged with supporters, raised money, and earned votes.

Hornall Anderson Design Works

11/2009 - 09/2011

Interactive Designer

Interactive design and development, motion graphics, and thoughtful UX for clients like Madison Square Garden, Empire State Building, HTC, Microsoft, Pepsico, and Hewlett Packard.

POP 10/2006 - 05/2009

Designer and Frontend developer

I designed, built, and launched micro-sites, rich media banner campaigns, motion graphics, and 3d work for clients like Nintendo, EA, XBOX, Target, and Ubisoft.

Squad Studios

03/2004 - 04/2006

Designer and Frontend developer

Designer, developer, and wearer of all possible hats. We built websites, music videos, and e-commerce products for some of your favorite bands.

Education

The Art Institute of Seattle

2002 - 2004

AAA, Interactive Media Development

Dean's List, Alumni Hall of Fame, and occasional speaker.

Awards

1st Place at Hack4Congress DC, Seattle Show 2009, The FWA 2008, ADDY 2008, IAB Interactive Awards 2007